5paisa.com 2019-09-02

# Online Trading Privacy Policy | 5paisa.com

Welcome to 5paisa Capital Limited. The domain name www.5paisa.com (hereinafter referred to as "Website") is owned by 5paisa Capital Ltd a company incorporated under the Companies Act, 1956 with its registered office at Sun Infotech Park, Road No.16V, Plot No.B-23 Thane Industrial Area, Wagle Estate, Thane - 400604 (hereinafter referred to as “5paisa”).

For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, wherever the context so requires the term "You" or "User" shall mean any natural or legal person including Online and offline clients and the term "We", "Us", "Our" shall mean 5paisa Limited.

We at 5paisa respect the privacy of everyone who visits this website and are committed to maintaining the privacy and security of the personal information of all visitors to this Website.

We view protection of your privacy as a very important principle. We understand clearly that You and Your Personal Information is one of our most important assets. We store and process Your Information including any sensitive financial information collected (as defined under the Information Technology Act, 2000), if any, on computers that may be protected by physical as well as reasonable technological security measures and procedures in accordance with Information Technology Act 2000 and Rules there under. If You object to Your Information being transferred or used in this way, please do not provide the details of your information on the Website.

We and our affiliates will share/sell/transfer / license / convey some or all of your personal information with another business entity to carry out any business activity or re-organization, amalgamation, restructuring of business or for any other reason whatsoever. Once you provide your information to us, you provide such information to us and our affiliate and we and our affiliate may use such information to provide you various services with respect to your transaction conducted on www.5paisa.com.

Our policy on the collection and use of personal information and other information is outlined below.

5paisa may for the purpose of rendering its services, collect personal information such as:

  * Name, Gender, Residential / Correspondence Address, Telephone Number, Date of Birth, Marital Status, Email Address or Other Contact Information
  * PAN, KYC Status, Signature and Photograph
  * Bank account or other payment instrument details
  * Transaction Information: We read SMS to retrieve OTP sent by 5paisa during login or transaction related authentication
  * Any other detail for providing services

5paisa offers online platform System for carrying out trade transaction that collects such personal data or information to process your financial and non financial transaction requests. The information so collected may be shared with SEBI/ NSE/ BSE/Asset Management Companies of Mutual Funds / Registrar and transfer Agents / Collecting Banks / KYC Registration Agencies (KRAs) etc. solely for the purpose of processing your transaction requests or serving you better. 5paisa or its authorized agents shall not retain or store that information for longer than is required for the purposes except when the information may lawfully be used or is otherwise required under any other law for the time being in force. The information collected shall be used for the purpose for which it has been collected. By agreeing to avail the service offered by 5paisa you have agreed to the collection and use of your Sensitive Personal Data or Information by 5paisa. You always have the right to refuse or withdraw your consent to share/dissemination of your Sensitive Personal Data or Information by contacting the customer care. However, in such an event, you would no longer avail the services of 5paisa.

To avail certain services on the 5Paisa Mobile App, users are required to provide certain personally identifiable information for the registration process which may include:- 

  * Your Name
  * Email Address
  * Phone Number
  * Access to your phone’s SMS inbox records
  * Debit card, Credit card, Bank details and any other such information as required.

The Information as supplied by the users enables us to improve the 5Paisa Mobile App Services and provide you the most user-friendly experience. In some cases/provision of certain service(s) or utility(ies), we may require your contact address as well.

All required information is service dependent and the Company may use the above said user Information to, maintain, protect, and improve the 5Paisa Mobile App Services and for developing new services. We may also use your phone number, email address or other personally identifiable information to send commercial or marketing messages without your consent [with an option to subscribe / unsubscribe (where feasible)]. We may, however, use your email address and phone number without further consent for non-marketing or administrative purposes (such as notifying you of major changes, for customer service purposes, providing information about updates to 5Paisa Mobile App Services, billing, etc.).

Any personally identifiable information provided by you will not be considered as sensitive if it is freely available and / or accessible in the public domain. Further, any reviews, comments, messages, blogs posted/uploaded/conveyed/communicated by users on the public sections of the Site or an Application Store (like the App Store or Play Store) becomes published content and is not considered personally identifiable information subject to this Privacy Policy.

In case you choose to decline to submit personally identifiable information on the 5Paisa Mobile App/Site, we may not be able to provide certain services on the App/Site to you. We will make reasonable efforts to notify you of the same at the appropriate time.. In any case, we will not be liable and or responsible for the denial of certain services to you for lack of you providing the necessary personal information.

SMS Inbox Information: The 5Paisa Mobile App also collects partial payment data and other information arising out of transactions made from cards, banks or while using other services through the App user’s SMS inbox, after obtaining the User’s specific consent to allow the App to access the User’s SMS inbox.The 5Paisa Mobile App only accesses Business messages that originate from Alphanumeric senders. The 5Paisa Mobile App does not access messages that originate from ten digit phone numbers. The collection of such information is only limited to the extent that such data is available in the relevant messages. 5Paisa may also record the identity of the product or service and the price or fee paid or payable in respect thereof.

When you register with the 5Paisa Mobile App Services, we may contact you from time to time about updation of your personal information to provide the users such features that we believe may benefit / interest you.

When You use the Website or send emails or other data, information or communication to us, You agree and understand that You are communicating with Us through electronic records and You consent to receive communications via electronic records from Us periodically and as and when required. We may communicate with you by email or by such other mode of communication, electronic or otherwise.

If you visit/ log into our website just to browse, read pages or download information, we gather and store certain information about your visit automatically. This information cannot and does not identify you personally. When you register with or view our site, our servers automatically record certain information that your web browser sends whenever you visit our website. The kind of information that is gathered automatically include the type of browser you are using (e.g. Internet Explorer, Firefox, etc.), the type of Operating System you are using (e.g. Windows or Mac OS) and the domain name of your Internet Service Provider, the date and time of your visit and the pages on our website. We sometimes use this information to improve our website(s) design, content and primarily to give you a better browsing experience. This notice / policy is not intended to and do not create any contractual or other legal rights in favour of any user or viewer of www.indiainfoline.com or on behalf of any other party. However, users and viewers are informed that by using the website www.5paisa.com, they are deemed to have consented to the collection and use of information by 5paisa as stated above.

You may upon written request to us review the sensitive personal data or information provided. 5paisa shall ensure that any personal information or sensitive personal data or information found to be inaccurate or deficient shall be corrected or amended as feasible.

5paisa uses commercially reasonable physical, managerial, and technical safeguards to preserve the integrity and security of your personal information. 5paisa cannot, however, ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to 5paisa and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission of information, 5paisa makes commercially reasonable efforts to ensure the security of our systems. However, please note that this is not a guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards. To protect your privacy and security, 5paisa take reasonable steps (such as requesting a unique password) to verify your identity before granting you access to your account. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your unique password and account information, and for controlling access to your email communications from 5paisa, at all times.

Our website sometimes has links to other website(s) in the World Wide Web. The privacy policies of these website(s) are not under our control. Once you leave our servers, use of any information you provide is governed by the privacy policy of the operator of the site you are visiting. It is advisable to read their privacy policies for further information. Your browsing and interaction on any other Web site, including those that have a link on our Web site, is subject to that Web site's own rules and policies. It is advisable to read their privacy policies for further information.

5paisa provide notifications, whether such notifications are required by law or are for marketing or other business related purposes, to you via email notice, written or hard copy notice, or through conspicuous posting of such notice on our Website page, as determined by 5paisa in its sole discretion. 5paisa reserve the right to determine the form and means of providing notifications to you, provided that you may opt out of certain means of notification as described in this Privacy Policy.

Please note that this policy may change from time to time. If 5paisa change its privacy policies and procedures, 5paisa will post those changes on 5paisa website to keep you/users aware of what information 5paisa collect, how 5paisa use it and under what circumstances 5paisa may disclose it. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page. Please visit our website to keep yourself abreast of any changes to this policy.
